빅뱅이론 지난 시간
The Big Bang Theory...
내 오빠...가 베르나데트에게 푹 빠졌어
My brother-- he's got a big crush on Bernadette.
네가 인디아로 돌아간다고??
You're moving back to India?
뭔..일이야??
What's going on?
(웃음)
(laughs)
이건...이건 보이는게 다가 아냐 ㅋㅋ
It's-It's not what it looks like.
보이는게 뭔데?
What does it look like?
보이는 것이 다가 아니다.
It's not what it looks like.
계속 뭐라는거야?
What are you grinding about?
오늘 아침에 일어난 페니의 난제 말이야
Penny's brain teaser this morning.
페니와 쿠스라팔리..
nan
네 침실에서 나왔지.
emerge from your bedroom.
그녀는 헝클어져 있었고 라지는 이불 한장 걸치고 있었지.
She is disheveled, and Raj is dressed only in a sheet.
단 한 가지 단서는, "보이는게 다가 아니야."
The sole clue: "It's not what it looks like."
그냥 내버려둬, 쉘든.
Just let it go, Sheldon.
가능하다면, 그랬겠지. 그치만 불가능하니, 안할거야.
If I could, I would, but I can't, so I shan't.
페니를 아는 사람으로써,
Now, knowing Penny,
확실한 답은 페니가 성교를 했다는 거야
the obvious answer is, they engaged in coitus.
하지만...
But...
그게 보이는게 다가 아니라는 전제 하예,
since that's what it looked like,
우린 그걸 배제해야 돼
we can rule that out.
이제 써보자고
Let's put on
우리의 생각하는 모자 말이야, 너도 할래?
our thinking cap, shall we?
라지는 인도에서 왔지 그 더운 나라에서 말야
Raj is from India, a tropical country.
세 번째로 더러워(third world hygiene??)
Third World hygiene.
감염되는 기생충이 엄청 많아 예를 들면 요충같은 거 말야
Parasitic infections are common, such as pinworms.
응 요충들의
Mm-hmm. The procedure
절차는 말야, 먼저 기다리는 거야
for diagnosing pinworms is to wait
목표물이 잠에 들 때까지 말야
until the subject is asleep,
그리고 나면 그 벌레들은 공기를 위해서 항문으로 나오게 되지
and the worms crawl out of the rectum for air.
그래, 그렇게 말야!
Yes, just like that.
페니는 어쩌면
Penny could have been
감염에 대비해 라지의 항문쪽 요충 검사를 한거야!
inspecting Raj's anal region for parasites.
오, 이런
Oh, boy.
정말로 질린 친구군
That's a true blue friend.
걔들 같이 잤습니다, 명탐정님.
They slept together, Sherlock.
아냐, 못 들었구나?
No, you weren't listening.
페니가 말했잖아 그건 아니라고
She said it's what it looks like.
거짓말이야
She lied.
오.
Oh.
이거 쓰고 있는거 병신같아 보여
Don't I look silly sitting here wearing this?
♪ Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state ♪
♪ Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! ♪
♪ The Earth began to cool ♪
♪ The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools ♪
♪ We built the Wall ♪ ♪ ♪
♪ Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery ♪
♪ That all started with a big bang ♪
♪ ♪
Original Air Date on September 22, 2011
== sync, corrected by == == 자막 by 귀족코쟁이/배포자유/첫자막이에여 ㅋㅋ ==
== sync, corrected by ==
안녕
Hey.
...안녕
레너드, 이상하지 않아?
Leonard, is it awkward for you
네 절친중에 한 명이 네가 사랑했던 여성과
knowing that one of your dear friends had sexual intercourse
성적인 관계를 맺었다고 해서
with a woman you used to love
네 머릿속 깊은 곳에 그런 생각이 자리잡고 있다는게?
in the very place you lay your head?
아니, 난 괜찮아
No, I'm fine with it.
비꼬는 것처럼 들리는데
That sounds like sarcasm,
무시하지 뭐
but I'm going to disregard it,
왜냐하면 재밌는 주제가 있거든-- 페인트볼이야.
because I have an agenda-- paintball.
자세하게 말하면, 이번 주말에 있는
Specifically, the interdepartmental
토너먼트를 말하는거야.
tournament this weekend.
병사로써 좀 더 제대로 싸우려면
In order to function better as a fighting unit,
우린 작전들을 짜야돼
I thought we should establish a chain of command.
그러니까 내가
Now, it goes without saying
너희 셋보다 뛰어나다는 걸 뺴면,
that I would outrank the three of you,
의문이 남아있지, 바로 작전을 얼마나 짜야 하는가? 야
but the question remains, by how much?
자,
Now,
나를 별 네개짜리 장군인양 쳐다보지 마
I don't see me as some four-star general,
그런 장군은 본부 뒤에서 탁상공론이나 하고
back at HQ riding a desk
국방 비서랑 골프나 치잖아
and playing golf with the Secretary of Defense.
그렇다고 내가 병장 쿠퍼가 될수는 없어
But I also can't be Sergeant Cooper,
왜냐하면 그렇게 된다면
because that might lead you
너희들이 나를 regular joe(규칙적인 joe?) 처럼 볼꺼 같으니깐
to think of me as just a regular Joe.
생각이 좀 필요하겠지만, 너희가 그런다면.
This might take some thought. As you were.
너 무슨 문제있냐??
What the hell is wrong with you?
그래, 어쩜 그럴 수가 있어?
Yeah, how could you do that?
네가 뭔 상관인데? - 난 레너드 친구야!
What is it to you? - I got his back.
그래, 맞아. 넌 그냥 질투가 난 것 뿐이지 왜냐하면
Yeah, right. You're just jealous because it turns out
페니에게 내가 레너드 다음으로 2빠니까!
I'm Penny's number two choice after Leonard.
야, 내가 베르나데트랑 안 사겼으면
Hey, if I wasn't engaged to Bernadette,
아마 그건 나였을껄??
that totally could have been me.
아놔 좀! 쉘든이 차라리 낫겟다
Please. Sheldon would have been before you,
아님 너희 대신 고자가 낫겠어!
and he might not even have genitals!
왜케 신경쓰는데?! 90 00:04:20,523 -> 00:04:21,806 넌 내 여동생이랑 사귀고
Why do you care so much?
나랑 페니는 사랑한단 말야..
and Penny and I are in love.
뭐???!!!!
BOTH: What?!
여러분, 잠깐 참견을 하자면,
Gentlemen, if I may interject,
제 계급을 대위로 정했다는 걸 알리고 싶습니다
I've decided my rank will be captain.
대위가 커크, 크런치와 캥거루에게 적합했다면,
If it's good enough for Kirk, Crunch and Kangaroo,
나한테도 그럴꺼야
it's good enough for me.
너와 페니는 사랑하지 않아
You're not in love with Penny.
아냐, 사랑해!
Yes, I am.
카마데마 신이 우리에게 꽃으로 만발한 사랑의 화살을 쏜거야
The god Kamadeva has shot us with his flowery arrows of love.
누구?
Who?
그는 힌두 버전의 큐피트야
He's the Hindu version of Cupid,
근데 큐피트보다 나아 왜냐면 거대한 앵무새를 타고 다니거든
but way better, because he rides a giant parrot.
아놔, 라지! 넌 너에게 웃어주는 여자면 전부 사랑에 빠져
Raj, come on. You fall in love with any girl who smiles at you.
한달 전에는 하워드 약혼자한테 시까지 써놓고선!!
A month ago, you were writing poems about his fiancee.
잠깐만. 뭐라고?
I'm sorry. What?!
말도 안돼, 말도 안되는 소리야
Rubbish. He's talking rubbish.
"오, 베르나데트. 내 클라리넷을 연주해주오"
"Oh, Bernadette, please play my clarinet."
그건 아무에게나 할수 있는 말이야
That could have been about anyone.
근데, 넌 걱정할 필요가 없어
Besides, you have nothing to worry about,
왜냐면 난 이제 쿠스라페니의 어두운 반쪽이거든
because now I'm the dusky half of Koothrapenny.
아참 기록에 의하면, 난 고자가 아니야
For the record, I do have genitals.
내 물건은 기능적이고, 예술적으로 뛰어나지
They're functional and aesthetically pleasing.
(헐..)
(groans)
흐음.
Well.
(똑똑)
(knocking)
오.. 나가요!
Oh. Coming.
그래, 괜찮아.
Yup, that's good.
와인잔은 있었어야 해
Wine glasses have handles.
알콜 섭취의 주기를 잘 지키고 있구나
Keeping accurate track of your alcohol intake.
좋은 생각이야 네가 술을 덜 마실때
Smart idea considering how trampy you get
휘청거리던거에 비하면
when you've had a few.
내가 뭘 저질렀는지 들었냐...?
You heard what I did?
음, 난 네가 했는지 알아
Well, I heard you did.
(아오..)
(grunts)
오 신이시여
Oh, my God,
난 모든걸 망쳤어!
I screwed up everything.
난 레너드에게 상처를 줬다고..
I hurt Leonard.
라지한테도 마찬가지고..
I hurt Raj.
도데체, 난 뭐가 문제일까?
I mean, what is wrong with me?
내가 무슨 두 명인것 같애..
I feel like two totally different people--
지킬 박사와 창녀같이
Dr. Jekyll and Mrs. Whore.
너무 그러지 마
Don't be so hard on yourself.
캐서린 여제라는 이야기를 알어?
Do you know the story of Catherine the Great?
아닝.
No.
그녀는 러시아를 통치했지
She ruled Russia
그리고 1700년대 후반의 한 밤에,
in the late 1700s, and one night,
그녀는 성적으로 흥분했지
when she was feeling particularly randy,
그녀는 복잡한 도르래의 원리를 이용해서
she used an intricate system of pulleys
말과 친밀한 관계를 가졌지
to have intimate relations with a horse.
미..미안한데
I'm... I'm sorry.
그게 나랑 무슨 상관이지?
What does this have to do with me?
그녀는 종간 접목으로의 문란한 생활을 했지만
She engaged in interspecies hanky-panky,
사람들은 아직 그녀를 "여제"라고 부르잖아
and people still call her "Great."
난 네 평판이 아직 살아있다고 믿어
I'm sure your reputation can survive
네가 북실북실한 인도 꼬맹이와 했어도 말이야
you shagging a little Indian boy.
(노크)
(knocking)
(한숨)
(sighs)
이 망할 놈아!
You jerk face!
하워드한테 뭐라고 지껄였어??
What did you tell Howard?!
우리 사이에 썸씽이 있었다고??
Did you say there was something going on between us?
그는 그렇다고 알잖아!
Because he thinks there is!
빌어먹을, 그는 미쳐가고 있어!
He's completely freaking out!
안으로 모시겠습니다
Please, come in.
뭐가 문제야?!! - 어...
What the hell is wrong with you?! - Well...
네가 언제나 나한테 잘해 줘서, 나를 좋아하는줄 알았어
You were always so nice to me, I thought maybe you liked me.
난 누구에게나 잘해줘!
I'm nice to everyone!
미안해..
I'm sorry.
망할, 당연하지! 미안한게 당연해!
Damn right, you're sorry!
그리고 하워드한테는 우리 사이에 아무것도 없었다고 전해!
And you tell Howard there's never been anything between us!
당연하지. 저기, 베르나데트? - 뭐!!
I will. Hey, Bernadette? - What?!
니가 보기에 내가 페니와 사랑하는것 같애?
Do you think I have a shot with Penny?
어 당연하지! 넌 존나 귀여우니까!
Of course you do. You're a cutie pie!
이세상 어느 여자라도 너랑 사귀면 기뻐서 미쳐 날뛸껄!!
Any girl would be lucky to have you!
그거 알아? 난 이런일 이미 겪어 봤어
You know, I've done this before.
유치원에서
In kindergarten,
난 휴회 기간동안 제이슨 소렌센과 결혼하기로 되 있었어
I was supposed to marry Jason Sorensen at recess,
근데 수업이 끝나니깐
but by the time my class got out there,
걘 이미 첼시 히멜팜과 약혼했더라
he was already engaged to Chelsea Himmelfarb.
그래서 내가 뭘 했는지 알아?
So what did I do?
정글짐에 거꾸로 매달려서
Hung upside down from the monkey bars,
남자얘들이 내 팬티를 보게 내버려 뒀지
let all the boys see my underpants.
자신을 자책하지 마
You can't blame yourself.
네 전두엽이 너를 기뻐하게 하는데 실패하면,
When your prefrontal cortex fails to make you happy,
상대를 가리지 않은 성행위가 너에게 필요한 도파민의 홍수를 선물할거야
promiscuity rewards you with the needed flood of dopamine.
우리 신경생리학자들은 이걸 "생크 반응"이라고 부르지
We neurobiologists refer to this as the "skank reflex."
야
You know what?
여기서 나가자
Let's get out of here.
어디로 가는건데?
Where are we going?
내가 벗은걸 본 사람이 없는 곳으로
Somewhere where no one's seen me naked.
꽤 멀리 가야 할꺼야..
We may have to drive awhile.
으흠.
(clears throat)
미묘하게 좋은 패가 아냐. 안그래?
Subtlety isn't her strong suit, is it?
네 집에서 며칠동안만 지내도 돼?
Can I stay at your place for a few nights?
정말?
Really?
베프가 우리집에서 자는거라니..와!
A best friend sleepover? Yay.
와..당연하지..와아..!
Yeah, sure. Yay!
우린 팝콘을 만들고, 밤을 새고,
We'll make popcorn, stay up all night
내 비밀 언어를 가르쳐줄거야. 옵!
and I'll teach you my secret language, Op.
정말 재밌겠다 - 아냐
Sounds great. - Nope.
정말 "잼 있 그 에있 다우"인거지
Sounds "Gop Rop E A Top."
ㅋㅋ그래 난 이제 짐 좀 챙길게 - 아냐, 그게 아냐
Yeah, I'm gonna go pack a bag. - No, you're not.
Yeah, I'm gonna go pack a bag. 넌 이제 "지므 조오음 챙긹읽에."지.
You're gonna "Pop A Cop Kop A Bop A Gop."
정말 이 망할 위장 군복 입어야돼?
Do we really have to wear this camouflage crap
페인트볼 하려고?
to play paintball?
누가 말한거지?
Who said that?
레너드, 네 목소리가 들려
Leonard, I can hear your voice,
근데 보이질 않아!
but I can't see you.
난 안해, 쉘든
I'm not in the mood, Sheldon.
오! 거기 있었구나!
Oh, there you are!
레너드
Leonard,
네가 최근 일어난 일에 속상한거 알아
I know you're upset about recent events, and
그리고 널 도와줄 사람이 여기 있어
I have someone here to help.
에이미랑 이야기하고 싶지 않아
I don't want to talk to Amy.
아냐 에이미가 아냐
No, it's not Amy.
얘야, 잘 지냈니?
Hello, dear.
우리 엄마를 불렀어?!
You called my mother?
오 레너드
Oh, Leonard,
지금이 옳고 그름을 따질 때야?
is it really necessary to caption the obvious?
얘는 어릴 때부터 저랬어.
He's been like that since he was a toddler.
"봐, 엄마! 나비다!"
"Look, Mommy-- a butterfly."
짜증나지
Maddening.
무슨 일인데요 뭘 원하는데요
What's going on? What do you want?
쉘든이 알려줬어
Sheldon informed me
네가 심리적 격변을 겪고 있다고
that you're experiencing an emotional upheaval,
그래서 도와주려 왔지
and I'm here to help.
정말 기분좋네요
That's so nice.
자 이제 현실로 돌아와서
And we're back to the obvious.
그래, 무슨 일이니?
Now, what's up?
음...어...그래요
Well, uh... okay.
어..
Um...
페니와 다시 사귀고 싶진 않아요
I don't want to get back together with Penny.
노력해봤지만, 미친 짓이었고, 잘 돼지도 않았죠
We tried it, it was crazy, it didn't work,
근데 나는 받아들일수가 없어요
but I can't deal with the fact
내 친구 라지와 페니가 잤다는게..
that she slept with my friend Raj.
그리고 나서 전 라지 동생 프리아가,
And then I find out that Raj's sister Priya,
여덟 달이나 사귀었는데
who I've been going out with for eight months,
인도로 돌아간다는걸 알았죠
is moving back to India.
그래서 전 완전히 심란하고 너무 외로워요
So I'm just completely confused and alone.
이해한다.
I understand.
조언해주실 거라도?
Got any advice?
응. 기운내
Yes. Buck up.
저기요?
Excuse me.
엄마는 부모자식간의 관계와 발달에 대해서는
You're a world-renowned expert
세계적으로 전문가잖아요
in parenting and child development,
그런데 고작 한다는 말이 "기운내"에요??
and all you've got is "Buck up"?
미안하구나
Sorry.
기운내 이 계집얘야
Buck up, sissy pants.
..고마워요 엄마 한참 낫네요
Thanks, Mother. I feel much better.
내 도움이 더 필요하다면
If you need any more help from me,
아마존에서 내 책을 살 수 있어
my books are available on Amazon.
끈다
Logging off.
99...100.
...ninety-nine, one hundred.
꼭 액체 금속 폭포같아..
It's like a waterfall of liquid gold.
내 차례~
My turn.
(한숨) 그거 알아? 난 사실 내가 왜
(sighs) You know, I don't even know what the point
LA에 머물고 있는지도 모르겠어
of me staying in L.A. is.
여기로 오고 연기하는 일이라곤 하나도 한 게 없어
I haven't gotten a single acting job since I moved out here.
그나마 제일 나았던게
The closest I came was last month,
치질 광고 답신이 온거였어
I got a callback for a hemorrhoid commercial.
오, 그럼 네가 치질 대표가 되는걸 볼수 있겠네?
Oh, I could so see you being the face of hemorrhoids.
그니까..글치?
I know, right?
하아..
(sighs)
아마 다시 나브레스카로 갈까봐.
Maybe I should just move back to Nebraska.
안돼! 네가 가길 내버려 둘수 없어
No, I can't let you do that.
왜?
Why not?
똑똑똑
(knock on door)
내 생에 처음으로,
For the first time ever,
난 제대로됀 사회생활을 해봤어
I have a thriving social life.
그리고 어떤 압력도 없었지
And no pressure,
그러니까 난 너와 동고동락할거야
but it kind of lives and dies with you.
안녕 에이미
Hi, Amy.
페니한테 얘기할수 있을까?
Can I talk to Penny?
내 바퀴달린 침대의 손님과 문 밖의 남자라..
A guest in my trundle bed and a boy at my door?
내가 13살의 나한테 "정말 나아졌어!"라고 말하고 싶구먼
I wish I could tell 13-year-old me "it does get better."
내가 여깄는지 어떻게 알았어?!
How did you know I was here?
에이미 페이스북에 있던데
It's all over her Facebook page.
네 물건들을 방으로 옮길게
I'll take your stuff to the bedroom
서랍도 비우고 고마워.
and clear out a drawer. Thanks.
괜찮아. 글구 잘해봐. 알았지?
No problem. Try and keep it in your pants, okay?
음, 안녕?
So, hi.
잘지내?
What's up?
너 금요일에 스케줄 있나 해서
I was wondering if you're free Friday.
왜냐면 그때 "80년대 그리스인들의 밤"을 하거든
They're having a Totally '80s Night at the Greek.
Hall & Oates, Katrina and the Waves(??)
Hall & Oates, Katrina and the Waves
그리고 카자구구 그룹의 오분의 삼도 나오지(카자구구는 5명)
and three-fifths of Kajagoogoo.
아ㅋ
(chuckles): Oh.
이런..정말 좋을텐데.. 근데 중요한건..
Gee, that's really sweet, but the thing is...
아아...중요한게 있구나..
Aw, there's a thing.
들어봐, 자기. 나 그때 진짜 취했어.
Look, honey, I was really drunk
어젯밤엔 정말 큰 실수를 저지른거야
and made a huge mistake last night.
우린 같이 자지 않았어야 해.
We should've never slept together.
그건 우정을 파괴하는 행위였어
It's what ruins friendships.
우정을 섹스로 파괴해..?
You can't ruin a friendship with sex.
그건 마치...아이스크림을 망치려고 초콜릿을 뿌린다는 소리 같잖아
That's like trying to ruin ice cream with chocolate sprinkles.
이리와
Come here.
들어봐..
Just listen to me.
난 옛날로 돌아가고 싶어..
I want to go back to the way we were before.
알잖아, 친구 말이야
You know, friends.
뿌리지도 않고 (아까 초콜릿 뿌리는게 망치는 거였으니)
No sprinkles.
오.
Oh.
그래
All right.
고마워
Thank you.
하아...
(sighs)
음..그러니까..으흠
Well, uh... (clears throat)
친구로써, 이걸 아는게 좋을거야..음
as your friend, you might like to know that, um...
우리가 전통적인..의미의 섹스를 한게 아니라는 걸 말이야
we didn't have sex in the conventional sense.
오, 신이시여
Oh, God.
너 무슨 이상한 인도 물건 나한테 넣었냐
Did you pull some weird Indian crap on me?
아냐, 아냐.
No, no.
우리가 벗고 침대에 누웠을때
After we got undressed and jumped in bed,
네...네가 나보고 그...보호 도구가 있냐고 물었어(코ㄴ도ㅁ)
you-you asked if I had protection.
오..가지고 있었지? 그렇지?
Oh, you did, didn't you?
당연하지 맨날 들고 다니니까
Of course. I'm always packing.
어쩄든,
Anyway,
음..그걸 넣는데 문제가 좀 있었어
um, I had trouble putting it on
그래서 니가 그걸 도왔고...
and you tried to help and...
이게 전부 다 그녀가 쓴거야(지어낸 얘기??)
that was all she wrote.
그러니까, 우린 사실 제대로..
So, we didn't actually...
내가 했지(우리가 아니라)
I did.
너무 아름다웠어
It was beautiful.
오...!
Oh!
페니, 제발 제발 약속해줘
Penny, please, please promise me
이거에 대해서 아무에게도 말하지 않겠다고
you won't tell anybody about this.
당연히 안해 안그러지
Of course I won't. No, I won't.
오..그래..하아
Oh, good. (exhales)
음...내가 사람들한테 우리 사랑이
Um, can I tell people that our love
너무 빠르고 너무 밝게 빛났다고 할까?
burned too bright and too quickly?
"바람 속의 촛불" 처럼?
Kind of a "Candle in the Wind" deal?
당연하지
Sure.
좋아. 그럼 내가 그게 전부
Cool. Can I say it fell apart
네가"아기를 갖고 싶어" 라고 했고
because you were all, "I want to have your babies""
나는 무슨 "그러기엔 내가 너무 자유롭지 않아" 라고 해서 망친 거라고 해도 돼? (??) and I was like, "I'm too rock and roll to be tied down"? <-원문
and I was like, "I'm too rock and roll to be tied down"?
아니.
No.
그럼 내가 너를 백인으로(white man?) 망쳤다고 해도 돼?
Can I say I ruined you for white men?
다시 말하지만, 안돼.
Also no.
알았어. 그럼 촛불 얘기만이구나?
Okay, just the candle thing.
그래
Yeah.
좋아
Cool.
그래..친구
All right... friend.
응
Hmm.
또 올게
I'll see you around.
그래
Okay.
라지, 기다려봐
Raj, wait.
내 친구가 되어줘서 고마워
Thank you for being my friend.
페니?
Penny?
응?
Mm-hmm?
...다시 아름다워지고 있어
It's getting beautiful again.
자, 이게 구글어스 지도야
All right, this is a Google Earth view
우리의 전투가 이뤄질 곳이 나오지
of the field of battle.
아무것도 안 보이는데
I don't see anything.
로딩하게 좀만 기다려봐
Give it a second to load.
언제 로딩되니 at&t!(통신사)
Whenever you're ready, AT&T!
됬다, 자 봐봐.
Okay, here we go.
우리는 여기 있고 남쪽으로는 루미스 교수님과
This is us here. To the south is Professor Loomis
지리학과 건물이 있어
and the Geology Department.
트위터에 따르면, 그들에겐 썬크림이 부족해.
According to their Twitter feed, they're out of sunblock,
무슨 말이냐하면 그들은 나무를 바짝 따라오거나 흑색종(피부암의 일종)에 걸린다는 거지.
which means they'll have to hug the tree line or risk melanoma.
거긴 우리 끝부분이잖아
That's our edge.
우리가 빨리 이 산등성이를 넘으면
All we have to do is move quickly over this ridge,
돌에게 기도나 하는 창백한 얼굴의 새끼들이
the rock-worshipping pasty-faced bastards
뭐가 자기들을 때리는지도 모르고 죽을 거야!
won't know what hit them!
좋아, 움직이자
All right, let's move out.
쉘든, 잠깐만
Hang on, Sheldon.
넌 어떻게 나한테 네 동생이 인도로 돌아간다고 말 안할수 있어?
How could you not tell me your sister was moving back to India?
아마 성기의 어색한 비유를 쓰느라 바빴겠지
Maybe he was too busy writing clumsy penis metaphors
내 약혼자의 그걸 말야.
about my fiancee.
먼 소리야
Screw you.
그건 아주 아름다운 성기 비유였어
That was a beautifully written penis metaphor.
으음...얘들아 나 페이트볼할 기분이 아냐
You know what, guys, I'm not in the mood for paintball.
그냥 포기하는게 어때? What do you say we just bag it?
What do you say we just bag it?
난 괜찮아 - 그래, 나도
Fine with me. - Sure, whatever.
넌 퇴장할수 없어
You can't quit.
그건 전쟁에서 무례함이야
That's a court- martial offense.
어쩌면 벌을 받을수도 있어 예를 들면...
That's punishable by...
넌 갈 수 없어
You can't quit.
미안해, 쉘든. 그냥 지금이 게임하고 놀 때는 아닌거 같아..
Sorry, Sheldon, it's just not a good time for playing games.
이게 너한텐 게임이니?
This is a game to you?
음, 앤티텀 전쟁이 게임이니?
Uh, was the Battle of Antietam a game?
응? 로마의 약탈이 게임이니?
Huh? Was the sack of Rome a game?
응, 아니, 아니
Yes, no and no.
기다려!
Wait.
너희들이 전부 내가 너희를 용서한다는걸 알아줬으면 좋겠어
I just want you all to know that I forgive you.
이 반란이 너희 잘못은 아냐
This mutiny isn't your fault,
내 잘못이지
it's mine.
난 이런 작대기들을 얻었으면 안돼(계급장)
I haven't earned these bars.
비록 내가 리더쉽에 있어서 완벽하지 못하지만
Although what I lack in leadership,
보아하니 난 바느질로는 보상할수 있겠네
apparently I more than make up for in sewing.
내버려둬, 쉘든
Let it go, Sheldon.
집에 가는 길에 잠바 쥬스 사줄게
I'll get you a Jamba Juice on the way home.
안돼
No.
잠바 쥬스는 영웅들을 위한 거야
Jamba Juice is for heroes.
그리고 그게 바로 우리가 되려는 거지
And that's what we're going to be.
뭐하는 거야?
What are you doing?
커크, 크런치와 캥거루의 발자국을 따라 걷는거야
Following in the footsteps of Kirk, Crunch and Kangaroo.
우워워워!
(people shouting in distance)
지리학은 과학이 아니다!
Geology isn't a real science!
이 망할 새끼들아!!!
Damn those sons of bitches!
전부 죽여라!!
Let's get 'em!
페인트탄이나 먹어라!!
Eat paint!
우워워워!
(yelling)
만약 쉘든교가 있었다면
If there's ever a Church of Sheldon,
이것이 그 시작일거야
this will be when it started.
파파팟 슝슝
(paintball guns popping)
아야!
Ow!
고귀한 희생으로 우리를 승리로 이끈
I'd like to propose a toast
귀하께 토스트를 선사합니다
to the man whose noble sacrifice inspired our victory,
쉘든 쿠퍼 대위
Captain Sheldon Cooper.
건배, 건배
Hear, hear. Hear, hear.
미안한데, 난 소령이야
Excuse me. It's Sheldon Cooper.
내 마지막 숨으로써,
With my last breath,
내 스스로에게 진급을 해주었지
I awarded myself a battlefield promotion.
이건 꽤나 중대한 일이야
It's kind of a big deal.
똑똑
(knock on door)
안녕, 잠깐 시간 있니?
Hi. You guys have a minute?
어, 그래, 당연하지.
Uh, yeah, sure.
좋아.
Okay.
음...으흠
Um... (clears throat)
라지에게는 미리 말했지만 나는
Well, I already talked to Raj, but I wanted to apologize
너희들 모두에게 사과하고 싶어
to the rest of you for,
알잖아, 모든 걸 말야.
you know, everything.
제발, 페니, 내가 할게..으흠
Please, Penny, let me. (clears throat)
우리는 우리가 미치도록 아름다운 밤을 함께 보낸 것이
We've decided to let our crazy, wonderful night together
그저 하나의 추억으로 남겨두기로 했어
be just one of those memories you have
그리고는 슬플 때 돌이켜보는거지
and can call to mind when you're feeling blue
아니면 샤워할 때라던가
or you're in the shower.
야, 뭐하는 거야 퀵드로?(권총을 빨리 뽑아 쏘는 것)
Hey, what you doing, Quick Draw?
미안. 계속해
Sorry. Go on.
으흠
(clears throat)
어쨌든, 난 너희들이 모두 알아줬으면 해
Anyways, I wanted you guys all to know that I've been taking
정말 많은 생각으로 이렇게 힘든 결정을 내렸고 결과적으로
a really hard look at things and come to the conclusion
내가 자신을 비웃지 않으려고 하는 걸 말이야
I have to stop kidding myself.
난 연기에 소질이 없어.
I suck at acting.
이젠 네브레스카로 돌아가야 할것 같애
It's time for me to move back to Nebraska.
네가 떠난다고?
You're leaving?
..그래
Yeah.
네브레스카에서 뭘 하려고?
What are you going to do in Nebraska?
몰라.. 연기나 가르치지 뭐
I don't know, maybe teach acting.
미안 잠깐만
Oh, sorry. Hold on.
여보세요?
Hello?
페니, 들어봐. 난 네가 이 결정을 나랑 너의 관계가
Penny, listen, I hope you're not doing this 'cause of you and me,
나는 여친이 있고 넌 싱글이여서 그런게 아니면 좋겠..
because I have a girlfriend, and you're a single woman...
쉿! 내 에이전트야 내 에이전트라고!
Shh! It's my agent, it's my agent.
농담이죠..?
You're kidding.
오..이런
Oh, my gosh.
믿을 수가 없어!! 정말요!!??
I can't believe it! Really?!
오, 너무 기뻐요!
Oh, I'm so excited!
감사합니다!
Thank you!
정말 감사해요!
Thank you so much.
네, 끊을게요
Okay, bye.
치질 광고를 찍게 됬어!
I got the hemorrhoid commercial!
월요일에 시작해!
I start Monday!
네브레스카는 어쩌고?
What about Nebraska?
오, 네브레스카는 집어치워
Oh, hell with Nebraska.
난 스타가 될꺼야!!
I'm gonna be a star!
쾅
(door closes)
== sync, corrected by == == 자막 by 귀족코쟁이 ==
== sync, corrected by ==
물리학 가르치는거 생각해 봤어?
Have you ever thought of teaching physics?
탈 준비 됬니?
Ready to ride?
아니요...엄마
I don't think so, Mom.
오늘은 안돼요
Not today.
오, 내 딸아
Oh, sweetie.
또 치질이니?
Hemorrhoids acting up again?
엄마는 그 반도 몰라요
You don't know the half of it.
아냐, 당연히. 난 알아
Oh, yes, I do.
이걸 조금 발라봐
Try a dab of this.
"여성을 위한 장미향 약품-H(치질의 첫글자)?"
"Rose-scented Preparation-H for women?"
여기서, H는 "여자(Her)" 란다
Now, the "H" is for "her."
엄마가 자랑스러워요
I'm proud of you.
쉿!
Shh!
여기서 내 농담이 나와
Here comes my joke.
이젠 어때?
How you doing?
예쁘게 앉아 있죠 ㅎㅎ
Sittin' pretty.